# Tina Cai

## UX/UI DESIGNER

## CONTACT

Seattle, WA, USA

**(**206) 407-4205

tinacai.me

(in) in/tinacai97

### **SKILLS**

#### Research

Competitor analysis, user interviews, usability testing, user flows, user journeys, persona development, proof of concept creation

## Design

Information architecture, sketching, wireframing, rapid prototyping, UI design, mobile design, web design, accessibile design

## Software

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, PhotoShop, Miro, InVision, Marvel, Jira, VSCode, GitHub, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React

## **EDUCATION**

## **Product Design Certificate**

MAR 2022 - MAY 2022

Co.Lab, Cohort #10
Design Buddies Scholarship

## User Experience Design Certificate

MAY 2021 - JAN 2022

CareerFoundry
Front-End Specialization

## B.S. in Electrical & Computer Engineering

SEP 2015 - JUN 2019

University of Washington, Seattle Power Design Concentration

## **ABOUT**

I am a UX/UI designer with experience in front-end development and engineering. I combine my newly-found creative and well-practiced analytical mindset to craft experiences with and for people. When not designing, find me playing video games, baking, or practicing pilates

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **UX Design Specialist**

JAN 2023 - PRESENT

## **SAP • AppHaus**

- Synthesized research data and designed and iterated on a mobile solution to simplify farm maintenance for Pif Paf Alimentos
- Created a web-based proof of concept prototype of a vehicle tolling solution for the State of Florida

## UX/UI Designer (Contract)

JUN 2022 - DEC 2022

## Rowy

- Re-designed the authentication and onboarding process given strict external constraints, seeing a 15% increase in user sign up completion
- Designed new navigation, subscription, demo, and other upcoming features for both the Rowy product and website

## **Graduate Engineer**

JAN 2020 - APR 2021

### Arup

 Designed building power systems based on client and team needs, producing 100+ design deliverables across 13 unique projects

## **Engineering Intern**

JUN 2019 - SEP 2019

### Katerra

 Cross-checked engineering designs based on building owner and team needs, resulting in a design package of 80+ code compliant drawings for a multi-building apartment complex

## **Engineering Intern**

JUN 2018 - SEP 2018

## City of Tacoma

- Designed power systems for new residential homes, helping 20+ projects move forward in construction
- Performed site visits to communicate with customers, form feasible solutions for new projects, and facilitate existing project builds

## **PROJECTS**

### Mesh

MAR 2022 - MAY 2022

## [ tinacai.me/mesh.html ]

- Worked alongside a product manager and developer to design and ship a solution that empowers early-career tech talent to network
- Took responsibility of product HTML documentation and CSS styling to assist development team and ship proposed MVP on time

## Personal Design Portfolio

NOV 2021 - FEB 2022

## [ tinacai.me ]

 Designed and hand-developed an online portfolio to showcase design case studies and practice front-end development